For 2 years, the entire AI industry
agreed on how to give a model memory.
You chopped your documents into
thousands of fragments, turned each
fragment into a long list of numbers,
and paid to store them in a special
database. Then, this spring, one of the
most respected names in AI looked at all
of it and said, "Just use a folder of
text files." And it worked better. Now,
Google's turned that folder into an
official standard. Developers are
calling it the most obvious idea they've
ever seen, and they might be exactly
right.
The complicated version existed for a
reason. Everything an AI needs to do its
job is scattered. A metric's definition
lives in one database. Its logic in some
pipeline. The reason it changed in a
6-month-old pull request. And the rest
in the head of an engineer who left in
March. The standard fix was a thing
called RAG. You take all those
documents, slice them into chunks, turn
each chunk into a long list of numbers
that captures [music] its rough meaning,
and load them into a vector database.
Ask a question, the system grabs the
chunks that look [music] closest to it,
and hands them to the model. It works,
but it never remembers.
>> [music]
>> Every query starts from zero. The model
gets a fresh pile of disconnected
snippets and has to work out the same
connections it worked out an hour
[music] ago, and the hour before that.
That respected name, by the way, was
Andrej Karpathy, co-founder of OpenAI,
former head of AI at Tesla.
>> [music]
>> In April, he posted a short file to
GitHub for an idea he called the LLM
Wiki.
>> [music]
>> And it flips RAG on its head. Instead of
the model re-deriving everything the
moment you ask, you build the knowledge
up once [music] into a folder of plain
text files that link to each other. A
living encyclopedia the model can read
the way a developer reads a code base.
People hear a folder of notes and
[music] assume they're the one writing
the notes. Wrong way around. You don't
write [music] the wiki, the AI does. You
bring it new material and ask good
questions. It handles the summarizing,
the cross-referencing, the filing, all
the upkeep nobody ever keeps up with.
Karpathy's own line for it, Obsidian is
the IDE, the LLM is the programmer, the
wiki is the code base. The folder is the
part you own, the model is the worker
who maintains it. This is where Google
comes in. On June 12th, Google Cloud
took that loose community idea and
published it as a formal spec, the Open
Knowledge Format. The spec is almost
comically small. A bundle is a folder.
Every file is one concept, a table, a
metric, a playbook, whatever you've got.
The file's path is its name. Links
between files form a graph. There are
two special file names, one that lists
what's in a folder and one that logs
changes. And there's exactly one hard
rule. Every file has to say what type of
thing it is in one field. The spec also
orders any tool reading a bundle to
forgive almost everything. Unknown
fields, broken links, even files it
can't parse. An enterprise standard from
Google whose defining feature is how
little it demands
>> [music]
>> and how much it lets you break. You
could build it in an afternoon. One
thing Google dropped though, Karpathy's
instructions for how the AI maintains
the wiki. They kept the folder and left
out the part that keeps it alive.
Back to the reversal. The folder wins
and it wins for three reasons. First,
when the work happens. RAG [music] does
its thinking at question time. The wiki
does it once up front when the bundle is
built, connecting concepts, [music]
flagging contradictions, writing the
summaries. Pay that cost a single time,
then just read the finished answer.
Second, skill. A model can only hold so
much in its head at once, and a big
[music] company has thousands of these
files. Each folder carries a short table
of contents.
>> [music]
>> The model reads that first, picks the
one file it needs, and skips the other
9,000. It never chokes on the whole
library. Third, it's only text. It lives
in Git exactly like code. You can diff
it, review it in a pull request, [music]
zip the whole thing and hand it to a
model running offline on a laptop. You
don't need a database, a server, or an
API key to read it. If you can open a
file, you're good. Two quick mix-ups to
clear up. This isn't competing with MCP.
MCP is the pipe that moves data around
live. This is the cargo that moves
through it, and it's not an SEO trick.
Nothing in it helps a search engine find
you. It's private knowledge for your own
agents. The pitch is that the AI does
the bookkeeping humans always abandon,
but the spec has no mechanism to keep
anything current. There's a field for a
timestamp, fine. A field is not a
process. Nothing in the format updates
itself. This works beautifully when one
person owns one folder. On a shared team
folder, it goes stale in a month. Nobody
volunteers to tend it, and the agent
starts answering from knowledge that
expired back in spring. That's catch
one. Catch two is funnier. The whole
idea rests on AI being a tireless,
accurate librarian. In practice,
language models are bad at writing clean
markdown at scale. They botch the
formatting, mangle headers, invent links
to files that were never created. And
how did Google fix the messy librarian
problem? They didn't. They changed the
spec to order every reader to forgive
the [music] mess. That permissive rule
is damage control with a nicer name. The
deepest catch is the last [music] one.
The format standardizes the container,
not the meaning. The one required field
is a free-form label. Your team writes
BigQuery table. Mine writes table.
Someone else writes relational asset.
They're all valid, but each is speaking
a different language. You can ship the
box anywhere. Agreeing on what's inside
is still on you.
Strip all of this back and you land on a
line some developer wrote that stuck
with me. An agent is basically just a
folder of markdown files. Anyone can
write markdown. The skill is in how the
folder is organized. What's locked
versus what the AI can rewrite. What
stops it drifting over a long run. The
moat is invisible. Two folders can look
identical. One holds up in production
while the other slowly rots. You can't
tell which is which by reading the
files. No format can hand you that. Then
there's the part Google would rather you
skim past. OKF didn't come out of
Google's AI lab. It came from the
BigQuery team. Every sample data set
ships on BigQuery. The reference tool
that writes the bundles runs on Gemini.
And the easiest place to pour a finished
bundle is Google's own knowledge
product. The one they just renamed for
exactly this moment. If you've seen our
video on Gemma 4, I guess you can
already smell the strategy behind this.
Will it stick? Hard to say. The day it
launched, almost nobody outside Google
was using it. And [music] a standard
with one user is just a suggestion. It
could easily be the next Google project
added to their graveyard. The idea
underneath it has already won though.
The most overfunded field [music] in
tech spent two years and a fortune
convincing itself that giving a machine
memory needed exotic infrastructure.
Then a tidy folder of text files did the
job better. Whatever happens to the
format, that part isn't going back in
the box.