Designing a dashboard isn't that hard,
but orchestrating one is. And there's a
massive difference between UI that might
look good and UI that actually works
when you start using it. So, whether
you're live coding a new project or
creating a piece for your portfolio,
we're covering the three tells that
immediately give away you've never built
one before and exactly how to fix each
and every one.
>> [music]
>> The one thing that all dashboards have
in common is they're built to display
data. So, if we focus on building the UI
around the data we need to display, we
end up with a much more usable
experience. For example, take a look at
this table. It seems relatively
logically laid out, but clearly nothing
is driving the form. But, for example,
if we turned the department and
employment into chips or took these
numbers and right align them, things
start to shape up. We do this because
there's only a set number of departments
or employment statuses, and we right
align the numbers so the digits align by
place value. Then, we can augment this
further by truncating long text to give
more breathing room to the other columns
or even shade out rows of the table that
are inactive or deactivated. And when we
compare the before and after, we can
clearly see which is more visually
appealing to look at and importantly,
which is letting the data drive the
form. And the same is true for data that
probably shouldn't even be in a table in
the first place. This table definitely
works. Don't get me wrong, we could use
it, but the time delineated nature means
that this isn't the best format and we
aren't letting the data determine the
shape of the UI. Instead, if we were to
arrange this as a timeline, it starts to
become a lot easier to follow rather
than a time sorted table. This form
factor could then be tucked into a
sidebar pop out or made wider as a
second column beside the table, but
either way, now we're letting the data
drive the UI. And color is a very
important consideration when we do start
designing these tables. [music]
Landing pages, you can get away with a
lot, but dashboard colors shouldn't just
be sprinkled in to look nice. It should
come from the data itself. In these
activity logs, the red icon in the chip
draws your eye to it because the action
is urgent. The avatar is there because
your eye can associate who did what way
faster than reading a name in the
column. And once you're thinking that
way, it's a pretty simple jump to adding
a chart to roll up the data into a
summary. Because this data has a time
dimension, and our chart shows you that
instantly instead of making you hunt
through a timestamp column, just like
our previous example.
Often when I talk about hierarchy, I use
examples like this, where this card has
poor hierarchy, and this card has strong
hierarchy. But there's another type of
hierarchy based on what you show and
what you hide, and it's called
progressive disclosure. For example,
this share functionality isn't
permanently ingrained in the side of the
table since it's not that frequently
accessed and frankly not important
enough. Instead, we tuck it into a
popover so we don't have to rip the user
to an entirely different page. And
within this popover, the primary action
is of course the search box, which is
why it's immediately visible at the top.
A secondary action like removing a user
isn't overly important, so instead of
ingraining it in the UI, we show the
remove button on hover along with a
tooltip. We could be more explicit by
always having them, or even still more
explicit by having the full label
present. But since we're tight on space
and removing a user from sharing isn't a
main action, we progressively reveal it
as soon as the user starts to look for
that functionality. And what I've just
described is called the spectrum of
explicitness, where a global, always
visible share button is quite high,
whereas an icon to copy a cell on hover
is much lower on that same spectrum. And
Apple does the same thing really well in
their Reminders app. On swipe left and
right, it reveals useful but secondary
actions compared to actually checking
off the reminder. And if you think about
it, this is exactly what an onboarding
is. When a user lands on your app for
the first time, they shouldn't be
staring at a fully loaded dashboard
wondering where to start. A good
onboarding might start with a single
tooltip pointing at the most important
action. Once they've done that, maybe a
second one appears or a simple checklist
in the corner. You're not hiding
functionality, you're sequencing it so
that the user is never overwhelmed.
Compare that to explaining the entire
product in a modal with six bullet
points the second you log in and then
instantly forgetting the moment you
dismiss. And the best way to get a feel
for how to handle this, the progressive
disclosure, the spectrum of
explicitness, and the onboarding flows,
is to look at a lot of real software.
Which is exactly what today's sponsor
Mavin makes dead simple. They've curated
hundreds of thousands of screens from
real mobile and web apps. So, instead of
piecing together an onboarding flow, you
can search through hundreds of them.
They also just launched an MCP. So, you
can pull Mavin's full library directly
into your AI development. I had it throw
together a mood board for a banking app
with real screenshots and actual links
in about 2 minutes. If you're interested
in checking it out, the very first link
down below will get you 20% off.
A really important concept that AI has a
hard time wrapping its figurative head
around is that UI is as much about what
you can see as what you can't see. Like
for as much as this table works well and
looks good, additional functionality in
such a dense design needs to come from
parts of the UI that you can't
immediately see. This could be as simple
as a copy chip over the cells or perhaps
comment functionality with a small
triangle indicator. Here's all the UI
that you can see and then this is all of
the UI that you can't immediately see
but is still there. And it's not a small
amount. We need it all to actually make
any of this table function. Putting the
individual pieces together, the spacing,
the sizing isn't that hard but
orchestrating them does require some
thought. And this applies just as much
to the smaller items as it does to the
larger drawers, models, and elements
that have hidden components and states.
It makes it easier to see that new
features or elements often don't require
a dedicated page just to be better
thought through how they're implemented.
But, this isn't just true for dense UI
like tables. Think about moments in
software that you almost never see. An
announcement about a newly launched
feature or an onboarding pop-up
explaining how part of the product
works. But, what's missing pretty much
unequivocally on all beginner dashboards
are tooltips. We have to assume that the
user won't understand all of our icons
or that they might want more details or
information on ambiguous labels. It goes
to show that there's so much UI that's
hiding that's important for a finished
product. And with that, those are the
three subtle flaws that'll give away
that you've never built a dashboard
before. The data driving the form, the
right things hidden until they're
needed, and all the invisible UI that
makes the whole thing actually function.
If you want to check out Mavin, it'll be
the very first link down below. You can
get the link to all of the Figma assets
used in this video down there, too.
Thank you so much for watching, and I'll
see you in the next one.