The biggest challenge for software
engineers these days, assuming finding a
job is not on the list, is reviewing the
huge piles of code going into
production. It was a complicated task
since basically ever, and it's slowly
grown into one of the unsustainable
stuff we keep getting asked to do with
changes that look like, well, this.
So, there's two ways this can go, and no
disrespect to the gentleman here, but
you can accept all always I don't read
this anymore, or look up to one of the
best engineers in our generation who has
built a DevOps enterprise with his bare
hands and currently building the best
terminal in existence for the love of
the game. Mitchell Hashimoto, while
dealing with exact same challenges,
needed a code review solution, and he
found it. Now, before you start
screaming lazy get at me, yes, lazy get
is awesome and while you can review code
with it, it's not made for that, and it
surely doesn't pack this. In a world
where slop is a first-class citizen and
these guys are trying to tell you all
software engineers will be gone within a
year, yet their job openings list grow
quicker than NPM get supply chain
attacks, it's on you. I mean, on us to
stand up a gate or hold the door and
review code like pros. [music]
Hunk is all of the above and more. This
doesn't mean agents don't have their
place. On the contrary, I'm going to
show you exactly how and where they fit
into this workflow. Let's get into it.
>> [music]
>> Back to this tweet that caught my eye
last month. Hunk is celebrated by many
more than just Mitchell. Dax, one of the
founders of Open Code, also points out
it uses Open TUI, the framework by
Anomaly, the company behind Open Code.
Hunk was recently built by Ben Vinegar,
one of the previous founders of Sentry,
who now stands behind a company that
aims to become your AI PM. [music] Hunk,
as you probably learned by now, is a TUI
for diffs with a sidebar, syntax
highlighting, and GitHub-like diff
panels. If it rings a bell from previous
videos I made, you're not wrong. We'll
get to that. As we mentioned, hunk is
built on Open TUI by Anomaly and PR
diffs, which is an open-source diff
rendering library, which, by the way, is
itself built on Shiki, a syntax
highlighter. Talk about how NPM supply
chain attacks start, right? So, without
further ado, npm or brew install hunk
from their tap, and you're good to go.
The first two commands you'll notice are
hunk diff and hunk show. Diff is for
state changes, while show takes your
last commit by default. There are some
other options, but before we go in
there, let's take a second to describe
what is it that hunk gives us and how it
lines up against its competition. Hunk
gives you an interactive TUI, diff
static, delta, and other options. Users
know that this isn't the case with them.
And here's where it gets interesting, an
inline agent and AI annotation. Okay,
we'll see. Let's rewind [music] a
little. Everything starts here, GNU
diff, a tool that finds the difference
between two input files. It was first
released, please hold onto your chair,
51 years ago, when Linus was five. Diff
is everywhere. Over the years, the
concept was implemented into git diff to
help users find changes. And recently,
we've started seeing modern options like
diff-so-fancy, that is, if you can call
a pearl project modern. Then came along
delta, a fantastic configurable diff
pager in rust. In recent video, I even
discussed diffnav, which adds a TUI much
like the one hunk presents, but around
delta. Not bad, but not quite what we're
here to cover today. I'd be remiss if I
didn't mention lumen as well, a rust TUI
that forces me to see this every time I
run it. It's a great and even closer TUI
and great UX, but still not with the
killer features hunk offers, which we'll
see today. Hunk show pops a stacked git
diff with some surprising top navbar and
then honestly beautiful syntax
highlighting and changes with color
[music] coding. Each file shows line
numbers and how many added or removed
lines, and I'll add a key caster here to
show you the motions.
Control D or U to jump up and down as
you would in Vim. Square brackets to
jump between hunks. GG and shift G to
scroll to the top or bottom. And even
HJKL, the arrows in Vim, works as you'd
expect. Now, here's the mouse in action.
Opening these menus suggesting further
shortcuts and options like using E to
open the current files in your editor
like so, which you can then quit to go
back. You can toggle views stacked like
we've seen before or side-by-side
splits, which is my personal preference.
There are themes, which oh god, my eyes.
Anyway, yeah, themes. And lastly, there
are notes. This is finally where the
magic happens. Beyond everything here,
the simplest feature of all and in my
opinion the greatest, and why I'd use
hunk over the others, notes. Much like
GitHub comments, are line-based text
bubbles you can leave or have someone or
something leave for you. Yes, I'm
talking about AI, but wait. If you're
shipping software across more than one
stack, you already know this pain. Your
Python service loads secrets one way,
your Go binary another, and that one
bash script in CI is just sourcing a dot
env file and hoping nobody commits it.
That's the gap Keeper Security built
Keeper Secrets Manager to close. The
Keeper Secrets Manager SDK gives you
simple, fast, and efficient way to
access your secrets management
functionality from all popular
languages. So, however your services are
written, retrieving a secret looks the
same every single time. And when you
don't even need a full SDK, there's the
CLI, which bundles core secrets manager
vault interaction straight from your
terminal, a shell script, or any
software that can be launched from the
shell. That covers the parts of your
pipeline that aren't really app code at
all. Deploy steps, cron jobs, one-off
automations without you writing a custom
integration for each one. It's the same
zero trust zero knowledge vault
underneath whether you're calling it
from code or from the shell. One
consistent way to handle secrets across
every language and every script in your
stack. If you want to see how this fits
into your existing workflow, request a
demo at the link in the description.
Now, back to the video. Hit the little
plus icon next to a line and add your
note. You can add as many as you like
and scroll between them using opening
and closing curly brackets. These can be
deleted of course and if it wasn't
clear, these comments are not Git
tracked changes and would only reflect
in this session, after which they
evaporate. Not perfect if you ask me,
we'll talk about that. As mentioned
earlier, hunk shows reviews the last
commit, but you can ask for an extended
review from head for example on the last
two or more. It also supports Jujutsu or
JJ. For those of you who are unfamiliar,
there are a couple of quite
controversial, I must say, videos on the
channel which you're welcome to watch.
And by the way, this is the main reason
for Mitchell Hashimoto enjoying hunk.
Most other tools support Git or even
just GitHub for reviews. Hunk supports
both as a first class citizen. JJ is
amazing, I'll leave it at that. Hunk
diff is for when local changes are not
yet committed and this is the real magic
of hunk. Building on top of the notes
we've seen earlier, hunk's entire idea
of them is actually around AI notes.
There's agent workflows file under the
docs section which helps your agent
review the changes it made and believe
it or not leave comments in your code.
If this doesn't spark curiosity, I'd
quit this video now and do something
more productive, but if you're in, check
this out. I'll fire up Pi, the best
coding agent I've used so far and
another video on the channel you'd
probably want to add to your watch list.
I've seen people on Twitter run hunk in
Pi, but couldn't find a dedicated
extension. So, I figured let's
understand how it works first and then
let Pi do it for me. So, hunk comes with
a session command, and unless I missed
something, this command isn't for you.
It's for your agent. When you start hunk
diff or show session, in the background,
hunk is running a small server. You can
list these running sessions, and the
hunk review doc explains how to use the
review, add context, navigate, and add
comments. The workflow suggests a skill
and a generic prompt to provide first.
So, we'll use that. Let's have Pi
install that skill for itself in the
background while we set things up.
With the generic prompt, we make hunk
load the skill, help it a little by
asking it to run hunk skill [music]
path, and review our diff. Go back to
our live session, and there we go. Agent
notes commenting on non-structured
response body in my API endpoint. Let's
go harder on another a bit more
complicated change in a big project with
notes from agent living next to my own
side by side.
Now, there's one problem that screams
here loudly. While I love the TUI, the
UE, the way you can review and read
notes, this isn't very collaborative.
Sure, you can pull a PR and have my
local Pi review and provide comments,
but what then? It's not in sync with
tools like GitHub comments. I can't
share the session, and even if I could,
it's not the best method I can think of
for code reviews. I've seen some open
issues mentioning this, and I hope we'll
see something close to that in the
future. Other tools I've shared in the
past like gh-dash that provides a TUI
that integrates with other great
projects like Octo and Vim for code
reviews in GitHub that actually leaves
comments for others to see. More on that
in the video on the channel. Okay, so
not that, but what can you do with these
comments? [music] A couple years back, I
wouldn't have to ask the questions. It's
obvious. Fix them, right? But, we're in
a different era. Good or bad, I don't
know which one, but here's the next
step. Pi can now use the comments
created by its predecessor session and
ask something along these lines. Load
the hunk skill and use it for review.
The scale would have a way to list
comments and we'd ask it to inspect the
context and reload when it's done. I'd
also suggest going with babysitter here
to maximize quality results. More on
that on a babysitter video on the
channel.
Somehow, we haven't mentioned it yet,
but hunk stewie comes with a sidebar,
which you can toggle with S. The
sidebar, especially after review, is
extremely useful at showing both diff
changes in line and added code, but also
comments added marked in purple next to
the relevant files. By the way, all
navigation options are available to you
by hitting the question mark key or from
the menu above. Okay, good stuff, but
we're not complete here without some
sweet persistent configuration,
especially not when it comes to the
terminal.
Hunk comes with a tommel config file
that defaults to dot config under hunk.
You can set the version control of
choice, stacked view or split, theme,
line numbers, and even notes on or off
by default. And while catpuchin is
misleadingly is a word stated here, it's
not actually part of the available
default themes, at least not at the time
this video is recorded. If you're like
me and you're serious about your dot
files, you start with a dot files repo,
new config directory path, set your
changes and preferences, then stow to
make sure symlinks are reflected in our
dot config path as shown in the bottom
split. More on stow and dot files on a
separate video yet again on the channel.
The next time you reload hunk, all the
changes are reflected in the UI.
Before we part ways, there's one
additional configuration and an extra
feature you should know about both.
Those of you who aren't using git trunk,
there's a video on the channel, add it
to your list, but if you're stashing
changes, you'd be glad to hear hunk
comes with a stash sub command. I've
made a small change here on the API
great response. Quickly git stashing it
removes the change from the working
snapshot, which now lives under the
stash stack. Run hunk stash show. That
was a very hard sentence to say, and
there is the change. No need to pop and
restash. Super useful for stash changes
you're unsure about and would like a
review.
The second feature is you can use hunk
as your default viewer simply by
configuring Git to use it as its pager.
This can, of course, be done globally or
per project, which doesn't make a lot of
sense. But, once you have hunk pager
configured, Git diff will pop the
familiar UI with your configurations
with the two-way features like the
sidebar you love. What if you don't want
it by default? No problem. That's why
Git comes with aliases. Just set one for
diff or show or both like H show, for
example, with hunk pager in its core
config. Allow me to tie everything up in
this video by going back to the tweet
that started it all for me, specifically
touching the fact that hunk is a local
diff viewer. It's good, speedy, lovely
shortcuts, and everything we love in a
terminal. A comment below this tweet
asking if Mitchell knows about LazyGit,
which is borderline disrespectful,
having mentioned he's big on JJ, and
LazyGit is, well, not. And while I've
mentioned it briefly earlier, it's
better to see with your own eyes.
LazyGit is still my favorite GitOps
utility. It has everything you want and
need, including reviews, which you can
basically change to anything you like,
but it won't be as good as hunk. And as
the Unix philosophy purists like to
mention on every single video I make,
use the right tool for the job.
Hopefully, that tool does one thing and
does it perfect. [music] Is hunk staying
with me? It sure is. Is it perfect? No.
And yet, I do urge you to go back and
check the video I made around GH dash
and how it replaces GitHub UI
completely. Paired with Octo and Vim, it
can also perform reviews for you. But
still, hunk at this point is the best
I've seen at local reviews and their
management. Hopefully, in the future,
it'll be able to become more
collaborative as a utility. Assuming
we're still collaborating with humans.
Thank you for watching. I'll see you in
the next one.