Scientists at Deep Seek have invented
something amazing and exactly at the
right time when we need it most. You
see, we are entering the age of AI. But,
I am really surprised. I just found out
that the way these AI systems run on our
computers is incredibly inefficient. So,
if you want your AI assistant to answer
quicker, you need more compute power,
clear as day. But, you may find that as
you add more compute, it does not get
faster. But, how can that be? You know,
it's kind of shocking given that
companies are paying billions and
billions of dollars for more compute to
run these AI systems. How is this
possible? Imagine reading a book and now
imagine that every time you turn the
page, you forget about the characters.
That's not a great way to read books,
right? Here is what happens in practice.
Assume we have a huge brain the size of
a mountain and we want to talk about a
book. If the book is one page, we just
memorize that one page and just talk
about it, quick and easy. Now, imagine
that the book grows. It is now huge and
since we forget about everything the
moment we turn the page, ouch. If we
want to talk about it, we have to reread
it all the time. So, our brain is huge
and hungry, but there is a problem.
Information is coming in through a
straw. So then, we spend most of our
time not thinking, but reading slowly.
And that is exactly what the graphics
cards of today are doing when you run an
agentic AI system on hard problems. All
those billions of dollars sitting at 40%
utilization.
This is a horror story. That's a tough
problem. So, what is the solution?
Well, of course, you don't need all
those GPUs. So, send them to me.
Problem solved.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, so how did scientists at Deep Seek
solve it? Dear fellow scholars, this is
Two Minute Papers with Dr. Károly
Zsolnai Féhér. Now, of course, they say
you don't need a bigger brain. You need
a bigger straw. So, in today's systems,
there are AI chips that do the reading.
We call them prefill machines. They are
the straws, and they are completely
jammed. But, there are also different
kinds of machines in the network, the
decoding machines. And their straws are
nearly completely empty. They just sit
there, often unused. So, they say, "Use
those to do the reading, and have it
take a second path to the prefill
machines." Finally, it's a clever detour
that lets the brain do its job. But,
there is a problem. This shortcut takes
the same high-speed roads that the AI
needs for thinking. If we don't do this
well, "Hooray, we solved the traffic
jam." And when they ask us how, well,
>> [laughter]
>> by introducing another traffic jam.
Okay, so what is the solution for that?
Well, traffic control. On these roads,
thinking traffic gets priority. Memory
traffic, however, gets leftover space.
This is absolute genius because it does
not give you more compute. No, it gives
you access to the compute that you
already have. Okay, so what is the key
result? Well, hold on to your papers,
fellow scholars, because it speeds up
this whole network from 40% utilization
to about 80% utilization. In practice,
almost twice as much work from the
machine you already bought. That is an
insane jump in just one paper. I am
completely stunned. And the main use
case for this is when you have long
multi-turn agentic workloads. And they
give this technique away for all of us
for free forever. Woof. Now, it is not a
magic bullet for all AI agents to run
twice as fast. No, no. It is
situational. But it helps exactly in the
hardest situations where we need them
most. Long conversations, lots of data.
That's when things really slow down.
Also, note that this is not a shiny new
AI system that you can easily write
headlines about. It's not the brain.
It's a better road system to the brain.
It's something that you implement in a
data center when you serve these AI
systems. So, you don't see a lot of
headlines on this because it's not the
shiny thing that is easy to sell. But it
is absolutely brilliant. And I really
wanted to show it to you. And all of us
get value out of this kind of open
science. If this idea makes it to real
serving systems, it might lead to
cheaper AI inference for all of us in
the future. And they don't close it down
and keep this knowledge to themselves.
They give it all to us as a gift. How
cool is that? That is the power of the
papers. What a time to be alive. A word
of optimism and joy in a world where you
hear about doom coming from every
direction. Subscribe and hit the bell if
you enjoyed this. Here you see me
running the full DeepSeek AI model
through Lambda GPU Cloud. 671
billion parameters running super fast
and super reliably. This is insane. I
love it. And I use it on a regular
basis. Lambda provides you with powerful
Nvidia GPUs to run your own chatbots and
experiments. Seriously, try it out now
at lambda.ai/papers or click the link in
the description.